

1401-4132 Halifax Street, Burnaby, BC, V5C 6V1, Canada

□ (+1) 250-715-6128 | mikeachester@gmail.com | chester.io | mchestr | mchestr

Su	m	m	a	r۱	V
----	---	---	---	----	---

Senior full stack developer with 8+ years of complete product development lifecycle of successfully launched applications. My practical experience includes infrastructure automation, backend software development, application security, support, testing, and people management. I strive to keep up to date with the latest technologies and best practises and try to incorporate them wherever feasible.

Experience _____

Idemia Vancouver BC, Canada

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Project lead and backend Python developer working on core eSIM/SIM orchestration product
- Built highly available and distributed systems to asynchronously provision eSIM/SIM use cases from the ground up
- · Responsible for communicating, designing, developing, and delivering multiple client projects from start to finish
- Built devops tooling to troubleshoot problems in eSIM/SIM provisioning
- Technologies: Python, Go, Clojure, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Salt Stack, AWS

CA Technologies Vancouver BC, Canada

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug 2016 - Feb 2018

- Full stack Java developer on the API Management Portal product
- Responsible for designing, implementing, and testing real time API provisioning on remote API gateways
- Mentored employees on Python scripting and git best practices
- Built Python scripts to on-board new and existing customers
- Leader for an internal API first group, to help guide teams to develop APIs following best practises
- Technologies: Java, Python, Docker, Kubernetes, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, OpenShift, TeamCity Siaras

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Burnaby BC, Canada

May 2014 - Aug 2016

Feb 2018 - Present

- Core Python developer working on the Siaras cloudScape/cloudBurst product
- Involved in designing, documenting, implementing, and testing custom plugins for OpenStack
- Developed solutions for abstracting different cloud technologies into a single common OpenStack API layer
- Helped design and develop creative WAN solutions using a variety of technologies such as GRE, VPN, and L2 Gateway
- Implemented end-to-end tests which integrate into our CI/CD infrastructure
- Technologies: Python, MongoDB, OpenStack

Education

University of Victoria Victoria BC, Canada

BACHELORS OF ENGINEERING IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Sept. 2009 - May 2014

Publications and Awards

Dynamic web cache publishing for IaaS clouds using Shoal, Ian Gable, Michael Chester, Patrick

2013 Armstrong, Frank Berghaus, Andre Charbonneau, Colin Leavett-Brown, Michael Paterson, Robert Prior, Randall Sobie and Ryan Taylor

arXiv: 1311.0058

2013 **Undergraduate Student Research Award**, NSERC

References

Available Upon Request